<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-02T16:50:10+08:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Bunbury</title><link href="/blog/2025/05/bunbury.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bunbury" /><published>2025-05-10T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-05-10T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/2025/05/bunbury</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2025/05/bunbury.html"><![CDATA[<p>A couple of weeks after travelling to <a href="/blog/2025/04/sri-lanka.html">Sri Lanka</a>, I went a few hours south to spend a long weekend in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bunbury,_Western_Australia">Bunbury</a> and its surrounds. It is amazing how it becomes noticeably cooler and greener with such just a short journey. Walking around Bunbury is easy and pretty, although you are finished quickly since the town is surprisingly small. There is one main street, a couple of malls and a couple of streets full of big box stores. Restaurant selection is limited. The farmers market is still a great food-only supermarket. Prices seemed largely the same as Perth. Overall it felt like a large successful country town, which I suppose it is.</p>

<p>Other places visited:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donnybrook,_Western_Australia">Donnybrook</a> Apple Festival is very popular, it felt like there were thousands of visitors taking over this small town! And it does not seem to have much to do with apples - there was just a single stall selling apples (very tasty!) and few others selling “related” products. The event seems like a cross between a small agricultural show and and a large standard market.</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Australind,_Western_Australia">Australind</a> felt like a commuter suburb. There was a nice Italian restaurant though (forgotten its name).</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Busselton">Busselton</a> has become a tourist town. Despite being much smaller, the main shopping street was nearly as large as Bunbury’s. However, the shops there felt like they were mostly for visitors.</li>
</ul>

<p>Some photos from the trip are in a short slideshow <a href="/slideshows/bunbury_25.html">available here</a>.</p>

<p><a href="/slideshows/bunbury_25.html"><img src="/assets/slideshow/bunbury_25/bunbury_main.png" alt="" title="Bunbury" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="Travel" /><category term="Australia" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A couple of weeks after travelling to Sri Lanka, I went a few hours south to spend a long weekend in Bunbury and its surrounds. It is amazing how it becomes noticeably cooler and greener with such just a short journey. Walking around Bunbury is easy and pretty, although you are finished quickly since the town is surprisingly small. There is one main street, a couple of malls and a couple of streets full of big box stores. Restaurant selection is limited. The farmers market is still a great food-only supermarket. Prices seemed largely the same as Perth. Overall it felt like a large successful country town, which I suppose it is. Other places visited: The Donnybrook Apple Festival is very popular, it felt like there were thousands of visitors taking over this small town! And it does not seem to have much to do with apples - there was just a single stall selling apples (very tasty!) and few others selling “related” products. The event seems like a cross between a small agricultural show and and a large standard market. Australind felt like a commuter suburb. There was a nice Italian restaurant though (forgotten its name). Busselton has become a tourist town. Despite being much smaller, the main shopping street was nearly as large as Bunbury’s. However, the shops there felt like they were mostly for visitors. Some photos from the trip are in a short slideshow available here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sri Lanka</title><link href="/blog/2025/04/sri-lanka.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sri Lanka" /><published>2025-04-15T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-04-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/2025/04/sri-lanka</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2025/04/sri-lanka.html"><![CDATA[<p>At the star of April I spent a fortnight in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sri_Lanka">Sri Lanka</a> for a wedding. Perhaps half the time was spent on travelling (see below) and the wedding activities, but we managed some sightseeing along the way. Overall it seems like a nice place to visit, although I’m in no rush to go back (despite missing some good stuff like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sigiriya">Sigiriya</a>). People have said it is similar to the Bali of 30 years ago. I can see that, it seems to be a good place to relax by the beach. Some thoughts:</p>

<ul>
  <li>There are surprisingly few restaurants everywhere we went (except the Negombo tourist strip). We probably only had 3 meals at local eateries, and that took some effort. I thought perhaps they were there, but I wasn’t looking for the right signs. However, I checked with various online maps, then confirmed by talking to locals and other tourists. Apparently Sri Lankans don’t tend to eat out often and tourists spend most of their time at touristy places (so outside those places good luck!).</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colombo">Colombo</a> is jarring mix of run down building and new towers, often very close to eachother.</li>
  <li>You are dangerously gem deficient! Walking around the capital we were regularly approached by initially friendly men who quickly told us that we were lucky to be in town that day as there was a special one-day only sale at the best gem store in town. We must go! This was over many different days and stores. One was a little aggressive, but all eventually accepted we weren’t going anywhere with them.</li>
  <li>Expect to pay more as a non-local, sometimes by a lot. For example, when a taxi wanted more from us than a equivalent Australian taxi (which are not cheap) we tried Uber and got a car at tenth of the asking price.</li>
  <li>Security sometimes can be very tight, other times non-existent. Going into hotels and shopping malls we went through metal detectors and bag checks. However, other places like train stations had no security, often not even a ticket check. There was no visible security on the streets either (although it still felt safe). Presumably this is a holdover from the long finished <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sri_Lankan_civil_war">civil war</a> and more <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2022_Sri_Lankan_protests">recent protests</a>.</li>
  <li>The train network is extensive and amazingly cheap, but incredibly slow and often delayed. Don’t be overly concerned about going in the lower classes as long as you have a set seat. We went in reserved 3rd class for one trip - it was fine and was not that much worse than 1st (no A/C, but we had the windows open). Overall we spent two nearly entire days travelling a few hundred kilometers and back again.</li>
  <li>The surrounds of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hatton,_Sri_Lanka">Hatton</a> are pretty (not so much the town itself), but there is not much else. The main site seems to be <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adam%27s_Peak">Adam’s Peak</a> a sacred site at the top of a mountain and the destination for a lot of internal tourism. It is extremely busy!</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Negombo">Negombo</a> has a strip along the beach full of bars, restaurants, hotels, and shops of local arts. It seemed pleasant but definitely tourist focused. We had a very good fish meal there in a restaurant just off the strip on our last night.</li>
  <li>It was hard to find good flights to Sri Lanka. Avoiding budget airlines and overly long flights meant we had two options. Both arrived and departed near midnight. Relatively cheap though.</li>
</ul>

<p>Some photos from the trip are in a short slideshow <a href="/slideshows/srilanka_25.html">available here</a>.</p>

<p><a href="/slideshows/srilanka_25.html"><img src="/assets/slideshow/srilanka_25/hatton_main.png" alt="" title="Hatton" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="Travel" /><category term="Sri Lanka" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the star of April I spent a fortnight in Sri Lanka for a wedding. Perhaps half the time was spent on travelling (see below) and the wedding activities, but we managed some sightseeing along the way. Overall it seems like a nice place to visit, although I’m in no rush to go back (despite missing some good stuff like Sigiriya). People have said it is similar to the Bali of 30 years ago. I can see that, it seems to be a good place to relax by the beach. Some thoughts: There are surprisingly few restaurants everywhere we went (except the Negombo tourist strip). We probably only had 3 meals at local eateries, and that took some effort. I thought perhaps they were there, but I wasn’t looking for the right signs. However, I checked with various online maps, then confirmed by talking to locals and other tourists. Apparently Sri Lankans don’t tend to eat out often and tourists spend most of their time at touristy places (so outside those places good luck!). Colombo is jarring mix of run down building and new towers, often very close to eachother. You are dangerously gem deficient! Walking around the capital we were regularly approached by initially friendly men who quickly told us that we were lucky to be in town that day as there was a special one-day only sale at the best gem store in town. We must go! This was over many different days and stores. One was a little aggressive, but all eventually accepted we weren’t going anywhere with them. Expect to pay more as a non-local, sometimes by a lot. For example, when a taxi wanted more from us than a equivalent Australian taxi (which are not cheap) we tried Uber and got a car at tenth of the asking price. Security sometimes can be very tight, other times non-existent. Going into hotels and shopping malls we went through metal detectors and bag checks. However, other places like train stations had no security, often not even a ticket check. There was no visible security on the streets either (although it still felt safe). Presumably this is a holdover from the long finished civil war and more recent protests. The train network is extensive and amazingly cheap, but incredibly slow and often delayed. Don’t be overly concerned about going in the lower classes as long as you have a set seat. We went in reserved 3rd class for one trip - it was fine and was not that much worse than 1st (no A/C, but we had the windows open). Overall we spent two nearly entire days travelling a few hundred kilometers and back again. The surrounds of Hatton are pretty (not so much the town itself), but there is not much else. The main site seems to be Adam’s Peak a sacred site at the top of a mountain and the destination for a lot of internal tourism. It is extremely busy! Negombo has a strip along the beach full of bars, restaurants, hotels, and shops of local arts. It seemed pleasant but definitely tourist focused. We had a very good fish meal there in a restaurant just off the strip on our last night. It was hard to find good flights to Sri Lanka. Avoiding budget airlines and overly long flights meant we had two options. Both arrived and departed near midnight. Relatively cheap though. Some photos from the trip are in a short slideshow available here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Link Blog</title><link href="/blog/2025/02/link-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Link Blog" /><published>2025-02-03T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-02-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/2025/02/link-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2025/02/link-blog.html"><![CDATA[<p>I regularly find interesting webpages that I want to record for later viewing. Over time I fill in browser bookmarks or text documents full of them.  They tend to become lost with changes in computer or other problems. Most recently with a harddrive crash a few months ago (no important data was lost, but transient files like these bookmarks were unrecoverable). So I have decided to follow the <a href="https://simonwillison.net/2024/Dec/22/link-blog/">advice from here</a> to create a link blog, or at least the occasional post of links. Hopefully they will sick around a bit longer that way.  I’ll try to group links based on themes (gamedev, technical, finance, …) to allow for easier search later. Also, I will not post any paywalled links, replacing them with archive links if possible.</p>

<p>So to start, here are some sci-fi and history links…</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rex_Nemorensis">Rex Nemorensis</a> (Wikipedia) - In the early Roman Empire there was a priest at a small glade near Rome. To gain this position a slave had to escape, make their way to the glade, break a branch from a sacred tree, and then engage the current priest in a fight to the death. Wild.</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.thebyzantinelegacy.com/">The Byzantine Legacy</a> - maps/pictures/diagrams of Byzantine sites.</li>
  <li><a href="https://tenochtitlan.thomaskole.nl/">A Portrait of Tenochtitlan</a> - artistic reconstructions of the Aztec capital Tenochtitlan, at the time of European contact, based on current research. I enjoy looking at maps of old cities trying to imagine what they were like, and this is a step up from that. See also the paintings of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canaletto">Canaletto</a>.</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/feb/03/flooded-quarry-mysterious-millionaire-and-dream-new-atlantis-welsh-border-deep">A flooded quarry, a mysterious millionaire and the dream of a new Atlantis</a> (The Guardian) - I always find it surprising there isn’t more of this sort of thing compared to people trying to live on Mars. The bottom of the ocean is far more habitable than anywhere outside Earth (better water supply, better radiation protection, closer proximity to support, better gravity, etc).</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.indiewire.com/feature/best-sci-fi-movies-science-fiction-film-1201817994/">The 65 Best Sci-Fi Movies of the 21st Century</a> - Yes, it’s linkbait, but it’s a good list. I’ve seen the vast majority of the films, and most of the rest I know about and don’t want to see, but still a couple went on my watch list. It has some good uncommon films (like Endless). While they definitely deserve to be somewhere on the list, I wouldn’t put Nope, Under The Skin, and The Host in the top 10 (perhaps replacing them with Blade Runner 2049 and Arrival - although that would make it Villeneuve heavy).</li>
  <li><a href="https://archive.is/iifrP">Angry workers use AI to bombard businesses with employment lawsuits</a> (archive link to bypass the Telegraph paywall) - Following on from the sci-fi above, a while ago I read Accelerando, an interesting Charlie Stross book where AGI evolves from legal and accounting computer systems. This colours the way they act, so the singularity plays out with highspeed legal warfare. This article reminded me of that.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="General" /><category term="Links" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I regularly find interesting webpages that I want to record for later viewing. Over time I fill in browser bookmarks or text documents full of them. They tend to become lost with changes in computer or other problems. Most recently with a harddrive crash a few months ago (no important data was lost, but transient files like these bookmarks were unrecoverable). So I have decided to follow the advice from here to create a link blog, or at least the occasional post of links. Hopefully they will sick around a bit longer that way. I’ll try to group links based on themes (gamedev, technical, finance, …) to allow for easier search later. Also, I will not post any paywalled links, replacing them with archive links if possible.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Goals 2024</title><link href="/blog/2025/01/goals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goals 2024" /><published>2025-01-11T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-01-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/2025/01/goals</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2025/01/goals.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/blog/2024/01/goals.html">Last year’s goals</a> were a little unambitious (apart from the Ci2D one), so I mostly did ok…</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Return to a decent level of fitness and strength</strong>: Technically I think I achieved this goal. I am fitter and stronger than this time last year, but barely. It turned out my shoulder was not as healed as I believed at the start of 2024, and it quickly came to limit my ability to exercise at anything other than a maintenance level. And that is where I stayed all year.</li>
  <li><strong>Improve Spanish</strong>: I have kept this up all year, just doing a little bit nearly every day, and I have improved. I’m definitely not fluent, but getting slowly better.</li>
  <li><strong>Learn to 3D print (and then paint the result)</strong>: I have printed so much stuff and now have a large grey pile of shame. I know what I’m doing with the printer, and can do supports and simple maintenance without issue. Next up: learn to design my own models.</li>
  <li><strong>18 blog articles (including Jarrah Technology)</strong>: 15 posts. Failed the easiest goal! Mostly because gamedev work stalled out, so I didn’t have many JarrahTech posts. I have discovered I don’t feel particularly disappointed about not making this goal, which is a good sign it shouldn’t be one in future.</li>
  <li><strong>Demo quality Ci2D</strong>: I got distracted at the start of year by a webapp idea and taught myself Javascript to write it. The other 9 months I was just lazy.</li>
</ul>

<p>This year’s goals:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Return to a decent level of fitness and strength</strong>: Same as last year. Once again I think my shoulder is improving, so time to try testing it a little (when the temperature drops in my outdoor gym). <em>Fingers crossed</em></li>
  <li><strong>Improve Spanish</strong>: If I continue with a few minutes each day, I won’t get worse. I’ve managed that for over a year now. With a occasionally little bit more and continuing the grammar drills I’ve started doing in the last few weeks, I should continue to improve.</li>
  <li><strong>Start Ci2D</strong>: Just starting would be good, it has been too long!</li>
  <li><strong>Modelling for 3D printing</strong>: Being able to print is nice, but the real benefits will come if I can model my own designs and then print them. Just need to relearn Blender and give it a go.</li>
  <li><strong>Read books</strong>: In December I started reading books again (borrowed from the local library). I started with the entertaining <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Murderbot_Diaries">Murderbot</a> series (one left). There are so many more interesting books from the list I compiled over the last few years available at the library. I should read some. I’ll set a target of 12, one per month.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="Goals" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year’s goals were a little unambitious (apart from the Ci2D one), so I mostly did ok…]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boardgames of 2024</title><link href="/blog/2025/01/boardgames.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boardgames of 2024" /><published>2025-01-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-01-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/2025/01/boardgames</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2025/01/boardgames.html"><![CDATA[<p>Once again I tracked the boardgames I played through the year (similar posts for <a href="/blog/2024/01/boardgames.html">2023</a> &amp; <a href="/blog/2023/02/boardgames.html">2022</a>). Over 2024, I played 31 different games a total of 69 times. A high-water mark I doubt I’ll challenge this year (unless my online boardgame playing really expands). I had an attempt on the 5x5 challenge (playing 5 games 5 times each), but fell a single game short. The full list is below, with the ones I own in <em>italics</em>.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Game</th>
      <th>Plays</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/142526/battletech-alpha-strike"><em>Battletech: Alpha Strike</em></a></td>
      <td>9</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/180263/7th-continent"><em>7th Continent</em></a></td>
      <td>6 (sessions)</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/173346/7-wonders-duel"><em>7 Wonders: Duel</em></a></td>
      <td>5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/249590/nevsky-teutons-and-rus-in-collision-1240-1242">Nevsky</a></td>
      <td>5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/14105/commands-and-colors-ancients"><em>Commands &amp; Colors: Ancients</em></a></td>
      <td>4</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/15954/conquest-of-paradise">Conquest of Paradise</a></td>
      <td>3</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/128621/viticulture">Viticulture</a></td>
      <td>3</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/163154/falling-sky-the-gallic-revolt-against-caesar"><em>Falling Sky</em></a></td>
      <td>3</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/23540/shikoku-1889">Shikoku 1889</a></td>
      <td>3</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/205637/arkham-horror-card-game"><em>Arkham Horror</em></a></td>
      <td>2</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/107148/wings-of-glory-ww2-starter-set">Wings of Glory</a></td>
      <td>2</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/119890/agricola-all-creatures-big-and-small"><em>Agricola: ACGAS</em></a></td>
      <td>2</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/256960/pax-pamir-second-edition">Pax Pamir</a></td>
      <td>2</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/93/el-grande">El Grande</a></td>
      <td>2</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/281655/high-frontier-4-all"><em>High Frontier (full version)</em></a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/1540/battletech"><em>Battletech: Classic</em></a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/30549/pandemic"><em>Pandemic</em></a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/103885/star-wars-x-wing-miniatures-game"><em>X-Wing</em></a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/209003/commands-and-colors-medieval">Commands &amp; Colors: Medieval</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/332686/john-company-second-edition">John Company</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/169786/scythe">Scythe</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/316554/dune-imperium">Dune Imperium</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/332853/dom-pierre">Dom Pierre</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/259/atlantic-storm">Atlantic Storm</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/42052/vinhos">Vinhos</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/123570/strike">Strike</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/216132/clans-of-caledonia">Clans of Caledonia</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/127518/a-distant-plain">A Distant Plain</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/2583/18ga">18GA</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/111799/cuba-libre">Cuba Libre</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/132018/churchill">Churchill</a></td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Most of the Battletech games were played at various local clubs. Many of the rest were played at the monthly Strategy Boardgame WA club. Although there are a few from meetups with the WA Boardgame Association and one from the local 18XX aficionados (my unofficial name) meetup. This year I also started playing online - all the games of Nevsky, 18GA and two of the Shikoku 1889 games were played online at <a href="https://www.rally-the-troops.com/">Rally the Troops</a> or <a href="https://18xx.games/">18XX.games</a>. I had previously tried playing online with Vassal and was unimpressed, but these new websites are much better. Also, after having played a few solo games I don’t think they are for me. I find myself taking advantage of the simplicity or lack of creativity of my cardboard opponent in a way that does not translate well to playing against humans. Playing online seems a better option, or playing computer games specifically designed for solo play.</p>

<p>This year I sold two games: 7th Continent (too repetitive and long) and Arkham Horror (not able to get it to the table other than solo). I acquired a bunch of games - a few I purchased, but more as gifts. Only one of these I managed to play during the year: Commands &amp; Colors: Ancients. So there is a replenished list of owned but unplayed games I need to reduce. I am considering selling a few more games as they seem hard to get people to play, so I always forget the rules in the year or two between plays: Falling Sky; High Frontier; and Twilight Struggle. However, I’m leaning towards keeping them at the moment.</p>

<p>Here are my thoughts on some games I played multiple times this year, and haven’t previously reviewed:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Nevsky</strong>: Brutal and unforgiving wargame set in during the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1240_Izborsk_and_Pskov_campaign">Teutonic invasion of Novgorod in the 13th century</a>. This game requires and rewards careful planning of supply lines, equipment and an army’s length of service. Then winter comes and makes it all even harder. Also has an interesting command system so that if your plans go awry, you may have to pass a few turns until resetting. This is a clever game, that feels true to its setting, but I’m not sure it is a fun game for me. I’ll try to give it another go in a few months.</li>
  <li><strong>Commands &amp; Colors: Ancients</strong>: Fast block-based wargame set during the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Punic_Wars">Punic wars</a>, that has a card-based command system limiting your power to do things. A charge on the left flank may win the game, but if you don’t have a card that allows you to perform that charge then tough luck. Fun.</li>
  <li><strong>Conquest of Paradise</strong>: This is a very interesting and enjoyable game. A fast-playing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/4X">4X</a> set during the polynesian expansion with random island placement. There is a strong emphasis on the first two X’s: explore and expand. The 4th X, extermination, is rare - in the 3 games I played there were only 2 battles, both as the final game winning action. I saw more battles avoided through a dance-off!</li>
  <li><strong>Viticulture</strong>: Eurostyle worker placement game about the winemaking process. I played a few of these this year. This was probably the most enjoyable, but they were all quite similar and fun.</li>
  <li><strong>Falling Sky</strong>: Asymmetric wargame set in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gallic_Wars">Gallic Wars</a>. Long and complicated. It requires a great deal of concentration, which I like, but is corresponding hard to get people to play.</li>
  <li><strong>Shikoku 1889</strong>: A relatively gentle introduction to the generally unforgiving <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/18XX">18XX</a> genre. Build railways at the start of the industrial revolution, with the aim of maximising your personal wealth (as opposed to the railway companies’ wealth). These games have some clever tabletop implementation of financial concepts (like companies, IPOs and debt). I will have to try more of these.</li>
  <li><strong>Agricola: ACGAS</strong>: 2-player worker placement game. A smaller version of <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/31260/agricola">Agricola</a> (which I haven’t played). Very little player interaction, as you build up a small medieval farm. Now we have played a few times it largely always plays out the same way. Fun, but perhaps a little too limited.</li>
  <li><strong>Pax Pamir</strong>: I read the rules before playing this each time, yet still after 2 games I don’t know what is happening during the game. This tableau builder set in the historical <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Game">Afghani Great Game</a> seems simple, but that belies quite a bit of depth and strategy. An experienced player easily defeats a newbie. Do I want to put the effort in to be a good player? Not sure.</li>
  <li><strong>El Grande</strong>: I played this at WABA. A very interesting area control/hand management game with some special and hidden actions. After two games I hadn’t worked out a good strategy, at least not against my opponents. I like the initiative deck system where each player choses a unique starting priority (unique both across all players in a round, and across all rounds by a player) - high priority and you start first, but get few resources, or vice versa. I was less keen on the hidden units in the castille, but then I’m not a fan of memory tests. A good game, I’d definitely play again.</li>
  <li><strong>Arkham Horror</strong>: Coop cardgame which attempts to tell a Lovecraftian horror adventure story. I just played the introductory campaign that comes in the box, but many more can be bought as expansions. It is definitely grim and difficult. The game doesn’t care about your success and negative effects (and some positive) persist through the game so failure or compromise seems inevitable. Thus the theme is well captured. I like: that cards are dual use (for points or ability); the chitpull modifier system; and, that the story advances along two sequences (your story and the opponents plan). I like less that the story is fixed, so after playing it once it gets easier as you know what is happening and what to do. This is not as prominent as in 7th Continent, as each mission in Arkham is probably only played a few times and changes completely for a new mission (unlike 7th where most of the cards are the same across curses, so you do them over and over again). Replayability is enhanced by the expansions, but the cost adds up quickly. Still if my usual game group were interested then I would buy and play them, but (being keen on winning and not keen on coop) they are not interested.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="Games" /><category term="Board Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once again I tracked the boardgames I played through the year (similar posts for 2023 &amp; 2022). Over 2024, I played 31 different games a total of 69 times. A high-water mark I doubt I’ll challenge this year (unless my online boardgame playing really expands). I had an attempt on the 5x5 challenge (playing 5 games 5 times each), but fell a single game short. The full list is below, with the ones I own in italics.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">End of Year Games</title><link href="/blog/2024/12/eoy-games.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End of Year Games" /><published>2024-12-22T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-12-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/12/eoy-games</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/12/eoy-games.html"><![CDATA[<p>Some more games I played over the last 6 months of 2024.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/758370/Through_the_Ages/">Through The Ages</a></strong> (9 hrs) - A computer version of the well regarded card-based, civilisation building boardgame <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/182028/through-the-ages-a-new-story-of-civilization">of the same name</a>. Graphics are simple, presumably to match the tabletop’s physical cards. The game is reasonably complex, and it’s good to have the computer do the calculations for you. Not much else to say. It seems like a competent conversion, but I doubt people will want it unless they already have an interest in the original version.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/510420/The_Hex/">The Hex</a></strong> (1 hr) - A mashup of many genres in service of a story game with many secrets. Hard to define, it is by the same person as Pony Island (which I didn’t like) and <a href="/blog/2022/04/enough-gaming.html">Inscryption</a> (which I loved) - so if you know either of them, this is similar. It falls between those games both chronologically and in my appreciation. However, the genres and tropes it was playing with don’t interest me much, so I bounced off it hard. My advice, start with Inscryption and if you like that, move backwards through the others.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1162700/Midnight_Protocol/">Midnight Protocol</a></strong> (3 hrs) - Hacking game. Move around computer networks, run programs to break defences and steal. I’ve played a few of these and find them quite similar. This is a well made, but standard version. The marketing materials tout the keyboard only controls, but I fail to see why that is a notable feature. Good game, but felt too familiar to grab my interest.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1794680/Vampire_Survivors/">Vampire Survivors</a></strong> (30 hrs) - A novel bullet-hell game, where the player is the bullet hell. The player doesn’t need to shoot, your weapons automatically shoot for you on a set schedule/pattern - just like the enemies in a normal bullet hell. Start underpowered, running away from the enemies, and soon find yourself over-powered, blasting projectiles in a satisfying cacophony of shapes, colour and sound. In later stages the biggest difficulty is understanding what is happening on a very busy screen! But not to worry, because games all finish after at most 30 minutes, then its time to start over. A simple game with plain graphics and sound, but the gameplay is so well designed it becomes extremely addictive. I do not normally like this sort of game, but this is a big exception. A great game!</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/632470/Disco_Elysium__The_Final_Cut/">Disco Elysium</a></strong> (2 hrs) - I really wanted to like this chatty isometric RPG with tabletop (ie dice rolling) mechanics. It is set in a strange, but vaguely 70’s world, where you are investigating a murder, while various parts of your mind converse with you. Strange, but slow. I made a bad choice and the game ended abruptly after 30 minutes, so I needed to start again. Then it crashed on me after an hour (and wiped my saves). I didn’t have the motivation to restart and go over the same thing a third time. Showed potential, but not enough to hook me.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1434540/Zoeti/">Zoeti</a></strong> (6 hours) - Fantasy cutesy anime semi-deckbuilder battler where the player collects cards for actions and then draws from a normal deck of cards and uses that to power the actions. It also has a narrative story (although not one I found particularly interesting). An interesting idea for variation on the Slay The Spire system, but is otherwise extremely similar, and not as good (of course Slay The Spire is exceptional!). This feels like a mobile conversion, and some of the UI is clunky as a result. It is an ok game.</p>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="Games" /><category term="Video Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some more games I played over the last 6 months of 2024.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Netflix Games</title><link href="/blog/2024/11/netflix-games.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Netflix Games" /><published>2024-11-19T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-11-19T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/11/netflix-games</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/11/netflix-games.html"><![CDATA[<p>Did you know Neflix has games? I have been a subscriber for years and never played one of their games. Since I am likely to leave their site soon (for a little while at least), I thought I should try a few games before I go. All the below were played on an iPad and the time played is a guess as Netflix won’t tell me.</p>

<p><strong>Immortality</strong> (about 6-8 hours?) - I was keen to play this after greatly enjoying <a href="/blog/2015/07/her-story.html">Her Story</a>, a previous game by the same team. The player goes through the scenes of 3 films out of order to discover their mysteries. Scrub back and forth through scenes and access newly available scenes by selecting objects common to both. The problem is I didn’t know what the mystery was. I just aimlessly went through scenes. Even though a larger story did start to emerge, I never really lost that confused directionlessness. Perhaps as a result, I felt a lot more passive in this game than Her Story. I just lost interest, thinking I was a long way from the end, but reading the plot in online spoilers I had actually discovered most of the story. Interesting and well made, but too clever for its own good.</p>

<p><strong>Game Dev Tycoon</strong> (about 6-8 hours?) - Instead of actual game dev perhaps I could just play a game about game dev? This is a fairly simple and unchallenging simulation game, almost casual. You choose the genre/topic/platform of your next game and it gets reviewed and sells based on how much effort is put into various areas. Then repeat until you go broke or finish the game. If you play games semi-regularly then the appropriate actions are unsurprising, On my one and only game I got nowhere near bankruptcy. It has an indie charm, but I staring losing interest quickly, only continuing to the end to see if something changed or happened (it didn’t).</p>

<p><strong>Spiritfarer</strong> (90 minutes?) - Cosy basebuilder game where the player replaces Charon in ferrying the dead to the underworld. Only instead of a small rowboat, you have a large ship with various upgrades available (including a garden). In my time playing I didn’t ferry a single soul, instead spent my time collecting resources and talking with the local residents between life and death. Very slow and chatty, plus the controls on my iPad were awkward, so it quickly lost my attention. Not my sort of game.</p>

<p><strong>Monument Valley</strong> (1 hour?) - Good looking puzzle game. Not my thing.</p>

<p><strong>Moonlighter</strong> (4-5 hours?) - Pixel graphics, realtime roguelike where after each short run in the dungeon you take the loot back to your store and sell it for money. Or, use it to craft better equipment, but I sold most of it. You can also upgrade your home town and your store - a nice touch. Not too taxing, being defeated just delays you and it’s always possible to escape at a small cost. I found the iPad controls a bit annoying for a realtime game, the targets on the screen were too small when trying to touch them with my fat fingers. A good, almost cosy roguelike (I didn’t know that was even possible!), but started to feel repetitive.</p>

<p><strong>Exploding Kittens</strong> (1 hour?) - Card game translated directly from the popular <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/172225/exploding-kittens">tabletop version</a> (which I had not played previously). Has an evil (?) cat theme, trying to be funny. High variance, but very short and quick to replay so that is not a problem - I think the idea is you play multiple times in a session. When playing alone against the AI this was mildly entertaining, but I imagine it shines when played as a group party game.</p>

<p><strong>Terra Nil</strong> (3-4 hours) - A anti-city builder. It plays like a city builder (place and connect buildings on a map grid), but the task is to clean up a polluted site and leave it pristine after tearing down all the buildings previously built. Excellent idea, and its full of nice touches like the animals moving back in (and their happiness level according to the current environment). Again, I would describe this as cosy, is this a theme with Netflix games? Nice game.</p>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="Games" /><category term="Video Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Did you know Neflix has games? I have been a subscriber for years and never played one of their games. Since I am likely to leave their site soon (for a little while at least), I thought I should try a few games before I go. All the below were played on an iPad and the time played is a guess as Netflix won’t tell me.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intelligence?</title><link href="/blog/2024/11/intelligence.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intelligence?" /><published>2024-11-12T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-11-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/11/intelligence</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/11/intelligence.html"><![CDATA[<p>There appears to a common view on various corners of the Internet that current AI is crap, borderline unusable. A subset of those people suggest it will never be “good enough”. This is largely due to the mistakes made by the public-facing generative large language models (LLMs) that Google, Microsoft and other are determined to push on their users. They make lots of maths errors, they can’t count the number of r’s in strawberry, they just make stuff up.</p>

<p>I agree with some of this. Current AI tools are often not being used appropriately, considering a knowledge of their deficiencies and this can create a negative impression of the whole technology. Certainly LLM tools have been put into search engines to soon in my opinion. They need to make less mistakes before they provide an experience equivalent to what we had before. Similarly, why would a <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-65735769">lawyer use an LLM</a> without checking for hallucinations?</p>

<p>I also disagree with parts too. To me it seems partly a misunderstanding of what counts as intelligence and thus regularly moving the goalposts of a true AI definition.</p>

<p>I haven’t heard anyone suggest, as of today, we have a true artificial intelligence (some people refer to this as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_general_intelligence">AGI</a>). Instead there are various tools that we call AI for marketing purposes. However, in reaching this point I have seen many definitions of computer intelligence come and go.</p>

<p>When just starting out in computing, some (non-technical) people would tell me computers couldn’t be intelligent until they could beat humans at Chess or Go. Well those lines were passed in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_Blue_versus_Garry_Kasparov">1997</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AlphaGo_versus_Lee_Sedol">2016</a> respectively, but no one considers those systems intelligent in the human sense. There have been goals around the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_test">Turing Test</a>, but current systems regularly pass these tests (note that the versions you see online are usually trained to not appear too human!). Other suggestions are that the creation of various forms of art are the mark of intelligence, but modern systems can do that.</p>

<p>Is it good art? I don’t know. I do know AI tools create better pictures and music than I could. I don’t even know how to play Go. My maths skills are better than average, but I still make mistakes all the time. I have been known to speak nonsense and make stuff up. Does that mean I’m not intelligent? If we held humans to the same standards as AI tools, I’m not sure many people would qualify as intelligent. Imagine the dumbest human you know capable of getting by in society. I would definitely consider that person intelligent in the computational sense. In some specific areas computers can surpass that person’s capacities, but in the general case they can’t.</p>

<p>Over the last 32 years that I have been paying attention to the state of the art in AI, the progress overall has been astounding, especially over the last ten. Modern AIs may not meet all your specific expectations, but they are improving fast enough I wouldn’t be confident that situation will remain for long. Will that mean we have a true AGI? I doubt it (but without certainty) as I’m not certain what intelligence is other “I’ll know it when I see it.” It is far more likely to me people will redefine what AGI is (again) and then claim they have reached their goal or haven’t depending on their existing bias.</p>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="General" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There appears to a common view on various corners of the Internet that current AI is crap, borderline unusable. A subset of those people suggest it will never be “good enough”. This is largely due to the mistakes made by the public-facing generative large language models (LLMs) that Google, Microsoft and other are determined to push on their users. They make lots of maths errors, they can’t count the number of r’s in strawberry, they just make stuff up.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back to Games</title><link href="/blog/2024/09/back-to-games.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back to Games" /><published>2024-09-12T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-09-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/09/back-to-games</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/09/back-to-games.html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been too long. I’ve been playing the occasional game since the last set of reviews. Now there is enough for a blog post…</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1075740/Banners_of_Ruin/">Banners Of Ruin</a></strong> (13 hrs) - A deckbuilder set in a medieval world where all the characters are animals. It has all the usual mechanics you would expect: lots of unlocks; combo cards; a choice of events; non-combat events; etc. The novelty is from the ability to have upto six characters fighting on your side. Thus positioning becomes important, as does drawing enough cards to feed all those characters. The downside is it can become hard to remember which cards can be played by which characters (I made so many sequencing errors). Everything about this game is well-made and competently implemented. However, it just didn’t grab me. Competent, non-flashy - a good but not great game.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/993790/Ancient_Enemy/">Ancient Enemy</a></strong> (3hrs) - solitaire-like card set in a magical dark ages Wales. By the same people as <a href="/blog/2022/04/enough-gaming.html">Regency Solitaire</a>, it is so similar it could be a sequel except for the change in setting. The other new addition is occasional battles where your powers increase as you clear more cards and you can see what the enemy will do next. These battles make it too hectic for the relaxed experience of Regency Solitaire, but the battles are not exciting enough to make me play this, instead of Slay The Spire. An interesting attempt to merge two different genres, but not interesting enough to keep me playing.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1948280/Stacklands/">Stacklands</a></strong> (20hrs) - Its a deckbuilder, no a city builder, no a survival game. Clever little cross-genre game. Collect card packs to get cards and place them together to create new cards to build a village and keep the villagers alive in the face of starvation and constant attacks. Lots of achievements and goals kept me going past the usual 10 hour limit for builder games. However, eventually it succumbed to the standard busywork problem and so I stopped not far from 100%.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://playruneterra.com/">Legends of Runeterra</a></strong> (too many hours) - <a href="/blog/2022/10/back-again-gaming.html">See initial thoughts here</a>. Played some more of this and even ranked online for a bit. My conclusion is it is a bad game. It is out of my system now. This game has that collect-them-all addictive (or compulsive) drive to collect all the cards. Luckily it is F2P and is very generous with in game rewards (I got to 70% of all cards without spending anything). However the multiplayer version of the game is high variance. There are many high value cards that can easily swing a game. It just depends who draws their good cards first. Thus even the best decks have around a 55% win rate. So many times the RNG is going to mean you are wasting your time from the start - you or your opponent is just too unlucky to make for a good game. It turns into a bit of a grind - like poker, but without the excitement/stress of playing for money. I suspect this is a conscious decision by the developers, I suspect it helps with monetisation. Not a good use of time. Just toss a (slightly weighted) coin instead, it is just as much fun and much quicker.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1385100/Insurmountable/">Insurmountable</a></strong> (14 hours) - Climb mountains fighting the elements and a spooky time-loop story events in this kinda 3D roguelike. The climbing itself is ok, but the events on the mountain are fairly limited and repeat often. I understand this might be intentional given the timeloop, but still makes the game tedious. Once I got the same event 3 times on a single climb (no looping in sight). A good idea that just doesn’t translate well into a game (in this case at least). Skippable.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/461840/Zenge/">Zenge</a></strong> (30 minutes) - Casual puzzle game of moving shapes along tracks until a picture is revealed telling a story. I got through a third of the game in 30 minutes, stopped, and haven’t felt the need to go back.</p>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="Games" /><category term="Video Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It has been too long. I’ve been playing the occasional game since the last set of reviews. Now there is enough for a blog post…]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Malaysia (again)</title><link href="/blog/2024/08/malaysia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Malaysia (again)" /><published>2024-08-08T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-08-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/08/malaysia</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/08/malaysia.html"><![CDATA[<p>At the end of last month I was in Kuala Lumpur for a wedding. As I lived in <a href="/blog/tag/Malaysia.html">Malaysia</a> for nearly 5 years back before the pandemic, I greatly enjoyed just walking around and eating for a few days. Restoran Kin Kin still has great noodles; Pelitas is a good as ever; and, I remain unconvinced by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Durian">durian</a>. There are a lot more towers in the city now, including a couple of very tall ones, higher than the Petronas towers. Although it’s good to see the KL penchant for skybridges is unchanged. Kampung Baru is being slowly surrounded by high apartment complexes. The old UK High Commission (<a href="/blog/2014/03/compound-living.html">where I lived for a year</a>) is now another set of 3 massive towers, over 60 floors by my count and getting bigger! However, Ampang Mall (where I used to eat an excellent Nasi Lemak) is now a skate park, so not everything is getting taller.</p>

<p>After the wedding I went to Sabah and hiked up <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Kinabalu">Mount Kinabalu</a>. It is an elevation gain of roughly 2200m over 2 days to a final altitude of 4095m, the highest I’ve ever been. Luckily no altitude sickness for me this time (unlike <a href="/blog/2010/11/peru-photos.html">the Inca Trail</a>), but we were climbing at the slow “unfit” rate. The hike was well organised and not too uncomfortable compared to others I’ve done. Unfortunately for three quarters of the hike we could only see the trees around us due to the mist and rain (very common according to the guide). Only once we passed the treeline (and above the clouds) did the amazing views emerge.</p>

<p>Some photos from the trip are in a short slideshow <a href="/slideshows/malaysia_24.html">available here</a>.</p>

<p><a href="/slideshows/malaysia_24.html"><img src="/assets/slideshow/malaysia_24/kk_shadow_main.png" alt="" title="Mount Kinabalu's shadow" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="Travel" /><category term="Malaysia" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the end of last month I was in Kuala Lumpur for a wedding. As I lived in Malaysia for nearly 5 years back before the pandemic, I greatly enjoyed just walking around and eating for a few days. Restoran Kin Kin still has great noodles; Pelitas is a good as ever; and, I remain unconvinced by durian. There are a lot more towers in the city now, including a couple of very tall ones, higher than the Petronas towers. Although it’s good to see the KL penchant for skybridges is unchanged. Kampung Baru is being slowly surrounded by high apartment complexes. The old UK High Commission (where I lived for a year) is now another set of 3 massive towers, over 60 floors by my count and getting bigger! However, Ampang Mall (where I used to eat an excellent Nasi Lemak) is now a skate park, so not everything is getting taller. After the wedding I went to Sabah and hiked up Mount Kinabalu. It is an elevation gain of roughly 2200m over 2 days to a final altitude of 4095m, the highest I’ve ever been. Luckily no altitude sickness for me this time (unlike the Inca Trail), but we were climbing at the slow “unfit” rate. The hike was well organised and not too uncomfortable compared to others I’ve done. Unfortunately for three quarters of the hike we could only see the trees around us due to the mist and rain (very common according to the guide). Only once we passed the treeline (and above the clouds) did the amazing views emerge. Some photos from the trip are in a short slideshow available here.]]></summary></entry></feed>