<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title type="text" xml:lang="en">Cordinc Blog</title>
    <link type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cordinc.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link type="text" href="http://www.cordinc.com" rel="alternate"/>
    <updated>2023-11-29T17:29:05+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cordinc.com</id>
    <author>
        <name>Cordinc Blog</name>
    </author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2013-2020 Cordinc Blog</rights>

    
    <entry>
        <title>China</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/10/china.html/"/>
        <published>2023-10-06T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2023-10-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/10/china.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently spent nearly a month in China. A fortnight in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guangxi&quot;&gt;Guangxi&lt;/a&gt; (mostly &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hechi&quot;&gt;Hechi&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guilin&quot;&gt;Guilin&lt;/a&gt;) staying with a friend’s family, and then a few days each in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wuhan&quot;&gt;Wuhan&lt;/a&gt; (halfway between Guilin and Beijing on the train), &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beijing&quot;&gt;Beijing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shanghai&quot;&gt;Shanghai&lt;/a&gt;. I took hundreds of photos and could write a great deal, but will try to keep it succinct with some notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first day was spent in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nanning&quot;&gt;Nanning&lt;/a&gt; and I quickly noticed that the streets were quieter than expected. Almost all of the scooters on the road and about a fifth of the cars were electric so made little noise. It was easy to tell which cars were electric as they had green number plates while ICE cars had other colours. There were a wide range of electric car brands, most were local and I had never heard about them before. Tesla’s were common too. In Shanghai around half the cars seemed to be electric, but in Beijing and Wuhan it was around 10-20%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are lots of building sites, usually of huge towers but most showed no evidence of currently being worked on (that I could see). Of course I may have missed some signs or they just weren’t being worked on at the time I passed. Still it was noticable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travelling across the country we saw many wide navigatable rivers. Also everywhere was green and verdant. Farms seemed small (compared to Australian standards). A big one would be a few acres or more. Every bit of spare space was turned to cultivation: empty city blocks and roadside verges often had neat rows of fruit/vegetable plants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All the cities were clean (like Perth) and felt safe no matter what alley we walked down. Some of the villages were a little rougher (not much!) but that is to be expected in working agricultural centers. The vast majority of people we met (including security) were polite and friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High-speed trains are awesome. Quick to get on at the station, and a few hours later you are at the center of another city. They have a speed display between cabins and the highest I saw was 359km/h. Most train stations are monumental - so big they look half empty even with thousands of people in them (&lt;a href=&quot;/slideshows/china_23.html&quot;&gt;see photo slideshow&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once we left Hechi there was air pollution everywhere. Not too bad, I’ve seen far worse, but it was still noticable. The horizon looked grey and distant buildings would fade into it. I would sneeze or cough for a few minutes each morning when leaving the hotel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everything is done electronically. WeChat or Alipay is an absolute necesity. Train tickets, tourist site tickets, communicating with people, nearly everything we did was organised through WeChat. This worked fine until we reached Shanghai and found Alipay (which we didn’t have) was more popular, so we had problems getting things done (the ferry told us to go away).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All payment is electronic through WeChat or Alipay. In my entire time in China I didn’t see a single credit card (nor use one), nor a paper ticket and I saw cash twice: once a tourist at a tourist site and once a local paying at a market. Everything else either has you send money directly through an app or has a QR code for transfers. Street stalls, hotels, trains, taxis, even the binoculars at tourist sites have QR codes. Usually this is the only way to pay. The country runs on QR codes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It must be impossible to survive as an independent tourist in China without access to these apps. We had one person with WeChat (through a local relative) and used that. As non-residents it requires some planning to get them. I applied for restricted WeChat (payment, messaging and a few other things) and it took 15 days to get access. So for the first half of the trip I was completely reliant on other people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Also you don’t have to go far off the tourist trail before having great difficulty with English. Unless you have access to WeChat/Alipay and someone who speaks Mandarin I would recommend using tour groups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone has a fancy phone and spends most of their time staring at it (just like home :) Tiktok is incredibly popular, people would talk about it all the time. Public phone chargers are common and often unattended (you pay via QR code).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highspeed wifi or 5G is nearly ubiquitous, much better than in Australia. However, the Great Firewall is real and works all too well. If you want to access a website or service from outside China then bring a good VPN with you - no recommendations because the list of working ones changes every few months as the firewall is constantly updated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the south at least the local languages seem to be disappearing, with the younger generations using Mandarin, while the middle aged and older would still use their regional language as default.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;China is a nation of shopkeepers. So many shops or stalls everywhere. I also saw lots of delivery drivers with stacks of packages, so Internet shopping is clearly big business too. Who is buying all the stuff? I hope the rent on shops is cheap to keep overheads low.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water fountains sometimes had 3 settings: cold, tepid, and boiling hot. That is not an exaggeration! It was boiling water that people used for pot noodles.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We visited a couple of villages and the houses looked recent and decent, but they seemed empty. I am told people would move to the cities and then build a nice house back in the village but not live there (or only for short periods). The village’s permanent residents were mainly older or poorer people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A goat costs AU$400. I know because that is what we paid to provide one for a village feast. There were also ducks, chickens and geese just wandering around the village, but apparently people know who owns them. Ducks get carried around in little pastic bags with their heads poking out. Its cute, but they are often being carried to become dinner. The meat was definitely full of flavour, but also chewy. The tofu was noticable tastier than in Australia (but then our hosts were tofu makers by profession). All of the village alcohol is home made, carried around in very large bowls and quite strong. It was some kind of grain spirit (but I was told it was not rice). Alcoholism was an issue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ground floor of village houses were an extension of the outside. Some used it for equipment storage, or animals. A couple of places used it to store silkworms on a bed of mulberry leaves (&lt;a href=&quot;/slideshows/china_23.html&quot;&gt;see photo slideshow&lt;/a&gt;). A good way to earn extra money I’m told.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every house/apartment we visited had a large flatscreen TV and water filtration system. Some in the villages (but not the city) had scary exposed wiring that I told was usually done by the owner - the week before we arrived a friend of our hosts was electrocuted to death.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I often saw men smoke (like Australia over 30 years ago), but never saw a woman smoking. Men seemed to be drinking far more often too. Alcohol and cigarettes are cheap, presumably the tax on them is lower?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cities got more expensive as we travelled: Hechi &amp;lt; Guilin &amp;lt; Wuhan &amp;lt; Beijing &amp;lt; Shanghai. Shanghai didn’t feel much cheaper than smaller Australian cities (apart from the alcohol and street food). Also people became clearly taller once we left Guangxi.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After Hechi, we booked hotels through WeChat, but many had a no foreigners policy. All the hotels we stayed in were good, quiet and clean.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once we got to Beijing there was definite increase in police/military security. Before and after that city it was around but didn’t feel too much (we had our ID checked twice at all the train stations for example - but it was far quicker than at an airport). In Beijing we would be stoppped and have our ID and bags checked several times per day just walking around, plus extra at any tourist sites. It was always polite, fast and friendly (apart from Tianamen Square, where they gruffly checked every item in my bag individually and I had to wait for them to read each page of paper I was carrying). There were also many uniformed police or military standing, walking or marching around. Also lots more video cameras (about to London levels).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sometimes it seemed these checks were security theatre. Once I took a step too far and could see the screen of the guy checking my passport. I saw him enter an incorrect last digit of my passport number and then saw a big red warning message appear. He simply returned my passport and waved me through with a smile.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We went to visit a street market and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hutong&quot;&gt;Hutong&lt;/a&gt; (local alleyways) one of us used to frequent when they lived in Beijing for a few months 20 years ago. They no longer existed. They had been replaced by modern shops and apartments. Apparently a common occurrence. We did find a Hutong, but it felt very touristy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Forbidden_City&quot;&gt;Forbidden City&lt;/a&gt; is huge and a great place to visit. We spent half a day there and could easily have spent longer. Recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Wall_of_China&quot;&gt;The Great Wall&lt;/a&gt; is overrated as a tourist site. The wall is impressive because of its extent, something you will not be able to appreciate on the few kilometers accessible at a time. It is also very busy and could be renamed the Great Line of China. We waited nearly 3 hours in line for a leisurely hour on the wall, shoulder to shoulder with other tourists. I have to say the lines were well organised. Full of turns and broken into stages, it never seemed like there was that many people in front of you - until you turned the corner. Each new stage of the queue was like a new stage in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/&quot;&gt;5 stages of grief&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Guangxi apartments tended to have security grates over the windows. At the time I was told this was normal all over the country, but I rarely saw it anywhere else we went. Strange. I was also told that Guangxi had great water and it could be found bottled throughout the country, this was definitely true in my experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guilin is a tourist trap, everywhere we went the exit was through a gift shop or three. It is a pretty place, but I didn’t find it much prettier than areas around Hechi. I probably would have been more impressed if went there first.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many tourist sites sell icecreams in the shape of the tourist site. Reader, I succumbed to the herd instinct and bought one. They are better then I expected - not great, but decent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Guangxi there many shops selling scooter batteries with a poster of a benevolent &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donnie_Yen&quot;&gt;Donnie Yen&lt;/a&gt; gazing down upon the street. He was the only person on street advertising that I recognized. It was strangely comforting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some photos from the trip are in a short slideshow &lt;a href=&quot;/slideshows/china_23.html&quot;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/slideshows/china_23.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slideshow/china_23/forbidden_main.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Forbidden City&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Miniatures</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/06/miniatures.html/"/>
        <published>2023-06-06T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2023-06-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/06/miniatures.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Through the purchase of various bordgames I have acquired a large number of small miniatures. Most of them are just the monochrome plastic. I thought it might be nice to try painting them. However, I didn’t want to start by wrecking the minis of any of my current games, so I bought a learn to paint kit (from Reaper Miniatures) which came with a few test minis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behold the result of my labours:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/minis/minis1.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;First Attempt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not great, but not awful. They are each about 5 centimeters in height and at a tabletop viewing distance look “ok”. Of course if you get close or look at closeup photos, all you can see are the errors. So what did I learn apart from my eyesight is getting worse and my hands are unsteady?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The less paint per layer the better. It is easier to fix up a watered down bad stroke with another stroke/layer, rather than being stuck with too much paint hiding details or just in the wrong place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take regular breaks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a “mistake” brush handy. If paint goes where it shouldn’t, promptly brushing it with water will usually fix it up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They took about 3 hours each (one at a time), so try doing a few at once. Hopefully I’ll speed up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it is worth continuing. Next up I’m going to try some duplicate BattleTech miniatures.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Adelaide</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/05/adelaide.html/"/>
        <published>2023-05-03T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2023-05-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/05/adelaide.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I last travelled out of Perth, so it was nice to get away to Adelaide and its surrounds for a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adelaide seems like a very quiet city, it reminds of Perth in that regard. However, where Perth is all about the beach or river, for Adelaide it is all about wineries. Must be a nice place to live.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Adelaide city markets are definitely worth a visit - should be more places like this in Australia.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The little laneways around the edges of either end of Rundle St (not the mall) have some great alfresco dining.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The center of Adelaide is very well laid out and pleasant to be around. It is encircled by a park which is excellent planning (reminded me of the half-encircling Turia Gardens in Valencia).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The last winery in a winery tour should pay the tour organisers. Anecdotally, the last place on the tour makes the most sales since everyone is a little drunk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Going to wineries gets a bit repetitive - how many ways are there to say “this is a nice wine”?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is not much to see at the mouth of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Murray_River&quot;&gt;Murray River&lt;/a&gt; (Australia’s longest river), but the drive down there has some interesting sights (and of course, wineries).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Still using my iPhone for photos, maybe time to dump the old camera?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A week is more than enough to “see” Adelaide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some photos from the trip are in a short slideshow &lt;a href=&quot;/slideshows/adelaide_23.html&quot;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/slideshows/adelaide_23.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/slideshow/adelaide_23/vineyard_main.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Barossa vineyard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Blame</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/03/blame.html/"/>
        <published>2023-03-15T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2023-03-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/03/blame.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some time ago the news included a story about the British government hiring an Australian ex-politician to be a trade envoy during the Brexit upheavel. I thought this was an understandable move from the point-of-view of British politicians and civil servants. If it all went badly (as was likely) thay could just blame the Aussie and sack him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It reminded me of the blame management I sometimes saw while working at large firms. At a couple of places there was a layer of management usually above the team managers and below senior managers that had “taking the blame” as a big part of their implicit job description. At some places outside consultants seemed to occupy the same role. Officially they were always in charge of this or that project, but had no direct power to get work done. They had responsibility without authority. If things didn’t succeed they got the blame for events outside their control. The cynic would suggest they were just the sacrificial lambs to ensure the senior managers remained unblemished. Rarely did any technical (ie non-management) get serious blame for the larger problems. Smaller things we got the blame for all the time, often deservedly, but here I mean the larger failures noticable to senior management. I wonder if this was the same outside the IT world? I suspect in my world blaming the people close to the work (like Software Engineers) would be counter-productive as we could just leave and get another job very easily. I also assume senior management never considered themselves the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I developed a rule of thumb for identifying blame managers. If you job was to “coordinate” or other vague terms that seemed to describe a lack of concrete responsibilty, you were safe. You could probably worm yourself out of a bad situation. If your job was “delivery” or running a project and you did not actually have any resources or subordinates, especially if you are in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matrix_management&quot;&gt;matrix-based organisation&lt;/a&gt; - watch out!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Boardgames of 2022</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/02/boardgames.html/"/>
        <published>2023-02-15T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2023-02-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/02/boardgames.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have started tracking the boardgames I play during the year. In 2022 I played 11 different titles for a total of 34 games. That doesn’t seem like much to me (but there were also 6 games of my prototypes). Here is the list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Game&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Plays&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/173346/7-wonders-duel&quot;&gt;7 Wonders: Duel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/328871/terraforming-mars-ares-expedition&quot;&gt;Terraforming Mars: AE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/251658/sprawlopolis&quot;&gt;Sprawlopolis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/274364/watergate&quot;&gt;Watergate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/230253/star-realms-frontiers&quot;&gt;Star Realms: Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/227789/heaven-ale&quot;&gt;Heaven &amp;amp; Ale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/281655/high-frontier-4-all&quot;&gt;High Frontier (Space Diamonds version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/14996/ticket-ride-europe&quot;&gt;Ticket To Ride: Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/103885/star-wars-x-wing-miniatures-game&quot;&gt;X-Wing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/30549/pandemic&quot;&gt;Pandemic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/283864/trails-tucana&quot;&gt;Trails of Tucana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now some short reviews of the games I own and have played at least 3 times:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7 Wonders Duel&lt;/strong&gt;: this is a 2-player only version of the also excellent deckbuilder &lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/68448/7-wonders&quot;&gt;7 Wonders&lt;/a&gt;. The goal is to build an ancient civilisation by selecting cards from layouts of escalating power. Some of the cards are hidden until they can be chosen other are visible from the start. There are lots of ways to acculumate points and many strategies. You have to adapt to the situation and your opponent. This is an excellent game and so much fun. I’ll be playing much more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terraforming Mars: Ares Expedition&lt;/strong&gt;: the 2-player version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/167791/terraforming-mars&quot;&gt;Terraforming Mars&lt;/a&gt;, an engine building game where the players vie to contribute the most towards making Mars human habitable. The back of the box says it plays in under an hour but I never taken less than 90 minutes. So far there is little interaction with the opponent, but the depth of tactics and huge number of possibilities keeps me interested. A good game I’ll keep playing for now, but will it keep me interested when it is more familiar?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sprawlopolis&lt;/strong&gt;: 18 card city builder. Quick and challenging, you lay the cards down like tiles to plan out a city, while trying to satisfy 3 randomly generated scoring rules. Can be played solo. Everyone I have played this with loves it, and deservedly so. Great to carry around as time-filler between other things (as were all the plays this year).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FYI: 3 plays is the review minimum because that excludes Watergate. I like the asymmetric gameplay of that Watergate, but am worried one side may have an winning advantage - I need more plays before giving a fair review.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>15 years</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/02/15-years.html/"/>
        <published>2023-02-14T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2023-02-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/02/15-years.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first post published here was fifteen years ago this month. Now there are 436 posts in total (including this one) corresponding to a rate of 29 posts/year. The result is 2.6MB of ascii text and around 240000 words which means an average post is 550 words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the last similar &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2015/02/blog-stats.html&quot;&gt;meta post&lt;/a&gt; 7 years ago, I have removed all visitor tracking, so no cookies or comments (or at least there shouldn’t be unless someone is injecting them - let me know if you see any). The site is also hosted for free on Github without logs. Thus it is no longer possible to be sure how many people visit, or from where, or for how long. Although I suspect that the trend is downwards as there are less of the technical posts that picked up organic Google Search traffic in the past and more posts about games I’m playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the plus side, this blog no longers costs me anything (other than writing time). At the start it cost US$10/month for hosting plus my sysadmin time. Then it went to US$5/month + sysadmin as improving technology compared to my relatively static requirements meant I could use smaller systems. Now hosting a few GB of static site is effectively no cost, and certainly no cost to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2008/02/the-beginning-again.html&quot;&gt;very first post&lt;/a&gt; I detailed my reasons for creating this blog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The aim of this blog is to detail my attempts to create a business that exists on more just selling my time as a consultant; other programming projects I undertake; and any other nonsense I think about.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that last clause has been met :) It has been some time since the last programming post (other than advertising for my games). Most of my days are spent coding, but I rarely feel what I doing is notable enough for public comment. I should probably change that, and just force out some technical posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Goals</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/02/goals.html/"/>
        <published>2023-02-10T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2023-02-10T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2023/02/goals.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Why do I do this? Am I a masochist? Time again to assess &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2022/01/goals.html&quot;&gt;last years goals&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase strength and aerobic fitness&lt;/strong&gt;: As I write this, I am injured - a reoccurrence of an old foot problem. So my exercise plan is on pause. This happened a couple of times last year. The plan was to lose some weight and then push for new highs. However, due to injury, covid and other things I didn’t manage to start losing weight until November. Thus I am definitely not stronger this year. I have been cycling regularly (until my foot injury a couple of days ago) so I might be fitter aerobically. Call this one a partial success.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish and release SHD&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2022/12/release.html&quot;&gt;Done&lt;/a&gt;! There should be a patch release soon too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Common Library&lt;/strong&gt;: Done! Or at least done enough to qualify as a success.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computer prototype Ci2D&lt;/strong&gt;: Nope, not even started (but the plan is to start in March).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper prototype IPO, Ci2D, &amp;amp; maybe one other&lt;/strong&gt;: Done! I have decent, not obviously broken, prototypes of IPO &amp;amp; Ci2d. Both could use a few more iterations, but not too bad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18 blog articles (including Jarrah Technology)&lt;/strong&gt;: Done! There were 12 posts here and 14 on jarrahtechnology.com.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fix steps, reticulation, ceiling crack &amp;amp; shading&lt;/strong&gt;: Done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.5 out of 7. Not too bad actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to be as ambitious this coming year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase strength and aerobic fitness&lt;/strong&gt;: Once my foot heals it is time to get back on track. So I need to be aerobically fitter according to my HRM (currently 39 VO2max) and have personal bests for 5 reps (powerlifting rules) in bench press (90kg), overhead press (45kg), and pullups (102kg).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demo quality Ci2D&lt;/strong&gt;: Have something good enough to show other people (by my assessment).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continue on IPO &amp;amp; maybe one other&lt;/strong&gt;: IPO might have some potential. I should keep going with it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18 blog articles (including Jarrah Technology)&lt;/strong&gt;: Same as last year. Easy but just need to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fix the bedroom window issues, fix the terrace drainage problem &amp;amp; build a rabbit hutch&lt;/strong&gt;: Some things I’ve promised around the house.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paint at least 10 minatures, and have played all my boardgames&lt;/strong&gt;: I have taken up minature painting although my skill is severely lacking. I should give it a decent try. There are also 5 games currently in my boardgame collection I haven’t played - I need to change that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Release</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2022/12/release.html/"/>
        <published>2022-12-14T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-12-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2022/12/release.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just after the pandemic started, I used the time in lockdown to start writing a new computer game. Later I stopped because it was a mess, but soon after I started again. Now it is released! Since it was never supposed to be a full game (just an experiment to get things going again) I have greatly skimped on promotion and marketing. Ohh, and the name. It is called Space Hex Duel. It is a turn-based game of strategy and careful positioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jarrahtechnology.com/games/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.jarrahtechnology.com/assets/posts/ahb/capsule_lg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Space Hex Duel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a short trailer showing off the gameplay:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/62viGwySbjk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have put it up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.itch.io/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt; as a Pay-What-You-Want (PWYW) download (suggested donation US$2). I recommend interested people download it for free, and if they enjoy it and would like to say thankyou, then go back and donate. Maybe later I will put it out on Steam too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt; &lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://itch.io/embed/1823532?linkback=true&quot; width=&quot;552&quot; height=&quot;167&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.itch.io/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Space Hex Duel by JarrahTech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the info on the game is ( or will be) on its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jarrahtechnology.com/games/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Jarrah Technology webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I need to decide what to do next…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Back Again Gaming</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2022/10/back-again-gaming.html/"/>
        <published>2022-10-14T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-10-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2022/10/back-again-gaming.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since the last gaming post 6 months ago, I have cut down a little on game playing, but still played a few…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/871530/Radio_Commander/&quot;&gt;Radio Commander&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (5hrs):  A tactical wargame where you only have a map and radio to command your Vietnam war soldiers. You find out what is happening via radio reports and issue orders the same way. Adds an element of confusion to what is happening - have I updated the map with the latest positions? Guaranteed that you will make a mistake at least once and called down artillery on your own men. This is a brilliant idea, but just doesn’t feel compelling. Maybe it is too slow? Maybe you are too detached from the action? Worth a try, but I stopped half way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/jurassic-world-evolution&quot;&gt;Jurassic World Evolution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (5hrs): Manage escape artist dinosaurs at an tourist park in this pretty city builder. Seems heavily tied into the recent films, which I haven’t seen. Has the nice idea of needing the player to complete missions for various departments - with any ignored departments sabotaging the park in revenge (where is HR when you need them!). Ok game, but way too fiddly for me. You are always in-motion - clicking something, or just repositioning the camera after it has flown off somewhere (again!). I prefer a slower, more thoughtful builder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/596970/Sunless_Skies_Sovereign_Edition/&quot;&gt;Sunless Skies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (12hrs): I have a love/hate relationship with this story/trading/roguelike game with some legacy mechanics (so many mechanics for such sparse gameplay!). A sequel to Sunless Skies, it sees you traversing a dangerous map in a steampunk sky world in a flying steam engine. Better than its predecessor, but still problematic as it is so slow! I played for 12 hours and the vast majority of that time was just getting between stops. I got an hour or two of story, another hour of action, but the rest was nothing happening as I travelled. I only kept going because the story and non-travel gameplay is very good - but not good enough. This game did not respect my time and I have better things to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/760650/Hammerting&quot;&gt;Hammerting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (3rs): This game feels a little undercooked. As a crafting based colony survival game (a genre I generally do not enjoy), it would need to work hard to gain my favour. Short review - it didn’t. In just a couple of hours it crashed twice and the tutorial didn’t tell me much so I could never really get going when it was working. It also suffered from the common problem with this type of game: it is incredibly fiddly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/874390/The_Battle_of_Polytopia/&quot;&gt;The Battle of Polytopia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (3hrs): Cute casual 4X game. Played 4 times in 3 hours. Not super deep, but gives a quick hit of gaming goodness. Probably played enough now, but a decent little game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/235540/Warhammer_End_Times__Vermintide/&quot;&gt;Vermintide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (3hrs): Online cooperative FPS set in the medieval grimdark Warhammer Fantasy setting where you battle hordes of Skaven (rat people). I had decent fun bashing rats over the head with my hammer. However, everything about this game is built for online play with 3 friends, and since it came out in 2015, there are now no other players. Literally the lobby was empty every time I turned it on. Nice game, but so lonely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://playruneterra.com/en-us/&quot;&gt;Legends of Runeterra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (too many hrs, Riot doesn’t tell you): Free-to-play collectable card battler from the makers of League of Legends (Riot Games) and reusing that IP. Has a nice offline single player mode, so no need to fight against real people and all the work of following a meta which that entails. While the game uses many of the modern innovations of computer-bases CCGs, the single player version suffers from some RNG problems. In an online game, if your cards just don’t roll out out, too bad (next time design the deck better). Here (in single-player) you play predesigned decks so when atrocious luck screws you and wastes 10 minutes it is not your fault, but the designers. Otherwise a good game, and the monetization seems particularly gentle, so worth a look.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Hosting</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2022/09/hosting.html/"/>
        <published>2022-09-02T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-09-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.cordinc.com/blog/2022/09/hosting.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This website has moved. &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2013/08/site-move.html&quot;&gt;Since 2013&lt;/a&gt; it has been hosted on a small virtual server at &lt;a href=&quot;www.linode.com&quot;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt;. Now it is hosted through &lt;a href=&quot;www.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. I should mention I have been very happy with Linode’s service and cost, but their minimum service is still overkill for this simple static website. I continue to use Linode for the &lt;a href=&quot;www.concealedintent.com&quot;&gt;Concealed Intent&lt;/a&gt; game server (for now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why the move? Maintaining an Internet facing server is a pain. There are a number of threats and it is just not worth the time in upkeep. Or worse, no support is performed and the server slowly degrades, becoming increasingly vulnerable (of which I am guilty since 2019). With Github all that work is handled by someone else, and the cost is 100% less (Github is free on my current plan, but even if I need to go to the paid plan later it’s still 25% cheaper).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some useful side effects of going to Github too. The site uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTPS&quot;&gt;HTTPS&lt;/a&gt; always, without me needing to play around with certs! Also, I changed DNS provider to &lt;a href=&quot;www.cloudflare.com&quot;&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;, and so far their free service is great too - they even cache &amp;amp; compress the website so it should load super quick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I have been happy with the process and outcome. There was a bit of fiddliness getting the DNS setup due to lag in updates propogating, but that was it for problems. The only issue to solve now is how to handle automatic backups, but then Github is probably more reliable then me, so I’m not rushing (touch wood). Might have to look into moving Concealed Intent too, although that’s a much bigger task.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    

</feed>